Narrator: Phrasal nouns
Particle first
Narrator: 1
Speaker: His parents were actors, so his upbringing was rather unusual.
Narrator: 2
Speaker: We need to offer more financial support to people on low incomes.
Narrator: 3
Speaker: Both teams are on top form – it’s impossible to predict the outcome of the match.
Narrator: 4
Speaker: Just as we left the cinema, there was a sudden downpour, and we got soaked.
Narrator: 5
Speaker: I like that brand of sweeteners – they don’t leave any nasty aftertaste.
Narrator: 6
Speaker: When changes to immigration policy were announced, there was a public outcry.
Narrator: 7
Speaker: A series of political misjudgements eventually led to the downfall of the president.
Narrator: 8
Speaker: Her bad back is an unfortunate after-effect of her car accident.
Narrator: 9
Speaker: It will be sunny today, but the outlook for the weekend is rain.
Narrator: 10
Speaker: We were supposed to be working as a team, but I had almost no input.
Narrator: 11
Speaker: Could you give us an update on the progress of our house sale?
Narrator: 12
Speaker: After an emotional outburst, she ran into her bedroom, crying.
Narrator: 13
Speaker: People felt the aftershocks many days after the earthquake.
Narrator: 14
Speaker: Our initial outlay was high, but eventually we made a success of the business.
Narrator: 15
Speaker: The documentary is about the events leading up to the outbreak of World War I.
Narrator: 16
Speaker: There has been a very high uptake of the free courses we advertised.
Narrator: 17
Speaker: As a result of a downturn in sales, several stores have been closed.
Narrator: 18
Speaker: The entrance fee helps with the upkeep of the house and gardens.
Narrator: 19
Speaker: Your recommended daily intake of sugar is about six teaspoons.